<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Majestic Monolith</title>
    <link>/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Majestic Monolith</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 13:52:11 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Unsplash is Awesome</title>
      <link>/post/why-unsplash-is-awesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 13:52:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/why-unsplash-is-awesome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The internet is full of wonderful people sharing knowledge and resources. Creatives and developers alike figure out new challenges and share their findings. We can see this in action on Github, Dribbble, Behance, Twitter and other social sites on the web. One thing that is hard to find is beautiful and usable photography. You can poke around Flickr. You can look for Google Images. You may get lucky and find photographs that are free to use. You may be able to use them without restriction, or attribution. And, you may be able to use them for commercial products or services. No guarantees. Welcome to Unsplash!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unsplash shares &lt;a href=&#34;https://unsplash.com/&#34;&gt;photos you can use online or in print&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Their pictures fall under the Creative Commons Zero license. This means you can do anything you like with the pictures you use. There are no commercial restrictions. You can slice them. You can dice them. Unsplash won&amp;rsquo;t even get mad if you put a Photoshop 7.0 lens flare filter on one of their pics. The sky is the limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, are they nice pictures? In my opinion, the pictures available on Unsplash are brilliant, professional photographs. They are interesting and thought provoking. They are a departure from the typical stock photo look and feel. I haven&amp;rsquo;t come across two business people shaking hands. I haven&amp;rsquo;t found that excited and well groomed customer service representative. The pictures feel more like real life. Or, at least a life we&amp;rsquo;d like to imagine as being real. Since they are all hi-resolution images you can use them on your website and printed materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Business Casual&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;image&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img
    data-src=&#39;https://res.cloudinary.com/dwjulenau/image/upload/c_fill,dpr_auto,q_auto,w_auto/v1479161837/unsplash-example.jpg&#39;
    src=&#39;https://res.cloudinary.com/dwjulenau/image/upload/c_fill,dpr_auto,q_auto,w_auto/v1479161837/unsplash-example.jpg&#39;
    alt=&#34;An image of sorts&#34;
    class=&#34;cld-responsive responsive-img&#34;
  &gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Artsy&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;image&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img
    data-src=&#39;https://res.cloudinary.com/dwjulenau/image/upload/c_fill,dpr_auto,q_auto,w_auto/v1479162150/colorful.jpg&#39;
    src=&#39;https://res.cloudinary.com/dwjulenau/image/upload/c_fill,dpr_auto,q_auto,w_auto/v1479162150/colorful.jpg&#39;
    alt=&#34;An image of sorts&#34;
    class=&#34;cld-responsive responsive-img&#34;
  &gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nature:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;image&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img
    data-src=&#39;https://res.cloudinary.com/dwjulenau/image/upload/c_fill,dpr_auto,q_auto,w_auto/v1479162320/yosemite.jpg&#39;
    src=&#39;https://res.cloudinary.com/dwjulenau/image/upload/c_fill,dpr_auto,q_auto,w_auto/v1479162320/yosemite.jpg&#39;
    alt=&#34;An image of sorts&#34;
    class=&#34;cld-responsive responsive-img&#34;
  &gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;There are many different categories from which to choose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a developer, you have a couple of options. You can go to their website and search for a particular keyword. This yielded better than expected results for my searches. They offer a series of collections that may prove useful. Mileage may vary, depending on your topic. They also offer &lt;a href=&#34;https://unsplash.com/developers&#34;&gt;Javascript and PHP API&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; for those who want to geek out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I would like to thank you, Unsplash&lt;/strong&gt;. Almost every image on this site is a representation of your offering. I appreciate your service and wish you the best of luck. Dear reader, I encourage you to head over to &lt;a href=&#34;https://unsplash.com/&#34;&gt;their website&lt;/a&gt; and poke around. There are no signups required. No trickery. No tomfoolery. Nothing to lose. Please share your thoughts below, and be sure to tell your friends if you like what you see on their site.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 21:07:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-majestic-monolith&#34;&gt;About Majestic Monolith&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The web industry seems to pride itself on complexity. But, Michael Peritore and Joshua Briley strive for simplicity. These guys have seen and developed overweight projects. They&amp;rsquo;ve used bulky libraries and frameworks. They&amp;rsquo;ve seen obscene amounts of money spent on hosting. &lt;em&gt;They&amp;rsquo;ve even seen 4 character HTML elements converted to 40 line React components&lt;/em&gt;. They&amp;rsquo;ve seen enough. They&amp;rsquo;ve had enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Majestic Monolith&lt;/strong&gt; is a &lt;em&gt;tongue-in-cheek&lt;/em&gt; reference to the mindset shared by Mike and Josh. They refer to all oversized and over-complicated projects as majestic monoliths. This blog aims to provide you with solutions that keep your web projects clean and simple. Kiss the unnecessary, monolithic web projects goodbye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-is-majestic-monolith&#34;&gt;Who is Majestic Monolith&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Michael Peritore&lt;/strong&gt; is the Lead Software Engineer for America&amp;rsquo;s Test Kitchen in Brookline, MA. He is an experienced Rails developer and enjoys architecting crazy simple backend solutions that wow the heck out of people. Follow Mike on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.github.com/primalcodes&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/MikePeritore&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joshua Briley&lt;/strong&gt; is a Senior Software Engineer for America&amp;rsquo;s Test Kitchen in Brookline, MA. He focuses on front end architecture, performance and UI development. His tools of choice are HTML, Sass, and Javascript (when needed). Follow Josh on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.github.com/somecallmejosh&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/joshuabriley&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-goal&#34;&gt;The Goal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things don&amp;rsquo;t need to be so damned difficult in this industry. They don&amp;rsquo;t need to be fancy. &lt;strong&gt;They need to be fast and they need to make money&lt;/strong&gt;. The goal of Majestic Monolith is to teach you to plan, program and manage web projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow this blog to or signup for our &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ikick.us7.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=8523d9263f5cc37057e16ab42&amp;id=a0784e376f&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to start learning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>