<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About-rsses on Majestic Monolith</title>
    <link>https://somecallmejosh.github.io/majestic-monolith-blog/about/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in About-rsses on Majestic Monolith</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 21:07:06 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://somecallmejosh.github.io/majestic-monolith-blog/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://somecallmejosh.github.io/majestic-monolith-blog/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 21:07:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://somecallmejosh.github.io/majestic-monolith-blog/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-majestic-monolith&#34;&gt;About Majestic Monolith&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The web industry seems to pride itself on complexity. But, Michael Peritore and Joshua Briley strive for simplicity. These guys have seen and developed overweight projects. They&amp;rsquo;ve used bulky libraries and frameworks. They&amp;rsquo;ve seen obscene amounts of money spent on hosting. &lt;em&gt;They&amp;rsquo;ve even seen 4 character HTML elements converted to 40 line React components&lt;/em&gt;. They&amp;rsquo;ve seen enough. They&amp;rsquo;ve had enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Majestic Monolith&lt;/strong&gt; is a &lt;em&gt;tongue-in-cheek&lt;/em&gt; reference to the mindset shared by Mike and Josh. They refer to all oversized and over-complicated projects as majestic monoliths. This blog aims to provide you with solutions that keep your web projects clean and simple. Kiss the unnecessary, monolithic web projects goodbye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-is-majestic-monolith&#34;&gt;Who is Majestic Monolith&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Michael Peritore&lt;/strong&gt; is the Lead Software Engineer for America&amp;rsquo;s Test Kitchen in Brookline, MA. He is an experienced Rails developer and enjoys architecting crazy simple backend solutions that wow the heck out of people. Follow Mike on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.github.com/primalcodes&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/MikePeritore&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joshua Briley&lt;/strong&gt; is a Senior Software Engineer for America&amp;rsquo;s Test Kitchen in Brookline, MA. He focuses on front end architecture, performance and UI development. His tools of choice are HTML, Sass, and Javascript (when needed). Follow Josh on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.github.com/somecallmejosh&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/joshuabriley&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-goal&#34;&gt;The Goal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things don&amp;rsquo;t need to be so damned difficult in this industry. They don&amp;rsquo;t need to be fancy. &lt;strong&gt;They need to be fast and they need to make money&lt;/strong&gt;. The goal of Majestic Monolith is to teach you to plan, program and manage web projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow this blog to or signup for our &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ikick.us7.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=8523d9263f5cc37057e16ab42&amp;id=a0784e376f&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;newsletter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to start learning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>